<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Alexander Vasin</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Alexander Vasin</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:1313/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>New York, New York</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/new-york/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I went to USA for a second time. This time I spend a week in New York only. This city is extra ordinal. It is huge in so many aspects. It has so many things to love as well as a lot of things to hate. I really enjoyed my stay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to share some places that I liked and of course some photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highline Park&lt;/strong&gt; is a great example of how to turn something old and ugly into beautiful thing. The park is built on abandoned railroad. It is nice place to have a walk or relax. I walked through all of it in early morning and enjoyed great view of the city and some fresh air.&lt;/p&gt;














&lt;figure&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;gallery/empire-state-building_8905195719_o.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Nice View from top of the Rock&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;gallery/empire-state-building_8905195719_o.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Nice View from top of the Rock
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;If you are going to climb Empire State Building consider &lt;strong&gt;Top of the Rock&lt;/strong&gt; on the Rockefeller Center as replacement. Not that it is better than ESB but it has different experience. First of all you are going to see ESB itself and Central Park from good perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second thing is that the Top of the rock is not so high. It might look as a lack but it turns out as advantage. The surrounding buildings look more impressive from Top of the Rock because you are closer to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the third advantage is that the lines are much shorter comparing to Empire State Building so you will go there much faster, especially if you booked it online in advance. At the end of the day I recommend climbing on to both of the observation decks - they provide gorgeous views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;American Museum of Natural History&lt;/strong&gt; is absolutely fantastic! We have not so many good science museums here in Russia so I was amazed. My personal favorites are Hayden Planetarium and IMAX movie. Plan in advance as you might spend there whole day. So many things are there.&lt;/p&gt;














&lt;figure&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;gallery/squirrel_8905790928_o.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Central Park squirrel&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;gallery/squirrel_8905790928_o.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Central Park squirrel
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Central Park&lt;/strong&gt; is one of the most popular places in New York. Go there in the early morning. At this time air is cooler and fresher and the park will not be overcrowded. If you like animals then aim for squirrels. There are a lot of them. Mostly they are very friendly and available for a contact if you have some peanuts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always add great places to eat to my trip plan. This time I visited several places and here are the best of them. &lt;strong&gt;Eileen&amp;rsquo;s Special Cheesecake&lt;/strong&gt; is a must visit place for everyone who loves desserts. This small bakery located at 17 Cleveland Place. You can eat there, take away and even order cheesecakes to your home. Their cheesecakes are piece of art. I hope someday I will learn to bake cheesecake tasting like those I tried at Eileen&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pete Luger Steak House&lt;/strong&gt; is another place I very recommend. This restaurant is located on 178 Broadway, Brooklyn and provides the most amazing steaks I have ever tried. There is nothing to add to it. Love steaks? Go to Peter Luger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is some photos from my both trips to USA. Hope you will find some time to take a look.&lt;/p&gt;









  
  


&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;//localhost:1313/post/new-york/gallery/1875_8905775380_o.jpg&#34; &gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/post/new-york/gallery/1875_8905775380_o_hu4e26234ce895e22accbe07cd9fa05267_5052232_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;//localhost:1313/post/new-york/gallery/5th-ave-apple-store_8905801272_o.jpg&#34; &gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/post/new-york/gallery/5th-ave-apple-store_8905801272_o_hu4e26234ce895e22accbe07cd9fa05267_6624196_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;//localhost:1313/post/new-york/gallery/911-memorial_8905814752_o.jpg&#34; &gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/post/new-york/gallery/911-memorial_8905814752_o_hu4e26234ce895e22accbe07cd9fa05267_3976045_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;//localhost:1313/post/new-york/gallery/atlantic-ocean_8905807288_o.jpg&#34; &gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/post/new-york/gallery/atlantic-ocean_8905807288_o_hu4e26234ce895e22accbe07cd9fa05267_4428408_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;//localhost:1313/post/new-york/gallery/empire-state-building_8905195719_o.jpg&#34; &gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/post/new-york/gallery/empire-state-building_8905195719_o_hu4e26234ce895e22accbe07cd9fa05267_5119106_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;//localhost:1313/post/new-york/gallery/squirrel_8905790928_o.jpg&#34; &gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/post/new-york/gallery/squirrel_8905790928_o_hu4e26234ce895e22accbe07cd9fa05267_4484945_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultural heritage</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/cultural-heritage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/cultural-heritage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love traveling and food. A rare person doesn&amp;rsquo;t like these two, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the intersection of these my two passions I love eating while I am traveling. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, I enjoy visiting new places and learning something new about them. In fact, I often conduct cultural research before I am headed somewhere. But I get bored pretty quickly with people that try
to watch every other sculpture that foreign country may provide. I do not mind sightseeing at all and there are many beautiful things to see in any country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty often there is a local food that has a very rich history too. For example, the history of Czech beer is older than the history of many famous Czech buildings. Any country can share some food features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like architecture, local food can be affected by other cultures. Some time ago there was no potato in Russia. Now one can not imagine Russian cousin without a potato.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People eat every day. In most countries. Next time you will be abroad, try a taste of local culture.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
